Family Circle and the Bison statue. I
would say every day I'm at work, I'm
working on that project a little bit.
>> What you're seeing is the main entry to
the building here through family circle
mini field down here. So this is going
to be a really activated area.
>> We can go out a little bit more to where
the bison roam.
>> So the physical form of family circle
has really taken off.
Part of what's happening out there is
that the beauty is you're starting to
see this is a great example that it's
coming to life. The circle itself and
the plinth or the base for the statues
that's complete. The area around that
where we're going to celebrate all the
great and Bill's history that's starting
to come together.
>> So you come, you know, you're hanging
out, you're having your lunch and behind
you is uh Thurman and next to him is Jim
and you just go down the list of all the
greats that will be behind you. So this
is these are designed as benches.
They'll all be illuminated very nicely.
So it's a very tastefully done.
>> It's an aspect that does not exist
across the street today that we felt was
really important for fans in the new
stadium and on this side of the road.
>> And the bison statues then are the
element that really are going to to
stand out.
>> So we've always shown some bison in the
renderings
>> and it's been several years in the
making. This is from 2022. And I wasn't
thinking of the design. I was just
thinking of can we put bison out front
of our stadium. So from the very
beginning we knew we wanted to do
something and I think then what happened
was how do we develop that?
>> What if there was a herd, right? What if
there's a herd of buffalo or what if it
was just a singular bison? And so we've
went through all those different
iterations to get to the final. And I'm
very excited for the direction that the
team wanted to go.
We're in beautiful sunny Lancaster,
Pennsylvania, and we're here at Art
Research and they're fabricating the
bison statues for us. Just overall
progress of details. It's not the
finished product, but we're getting to a
point where the fabrication technique
we'll agree upon and it's quality we
want and it's working, then we can
really start moving forward with
building out the three final pieces.
>> Well, my name is Blessing Hancock and I
am an international sculpture artist and
I am creating artwork for the new
Buffalo Bills Highark Stadium.
You know, Blessing has done work around
the world. She's a visionary designer
and so she uses firms to help then
execute on that vision.
And that's what they do for a variety of
artists, all sorts of mediums, bronze
and steel and and welded elements and
concrete and clay. And so that's been
really fun to watch.
>> I emphasize community storytelling and I
have a strong interest in abstraction.
So, it's been interesting to work with
the Buffalo Bills because the challenge
has been to combine my interest in
abstraction
on a representative form of a vice.
>> Uh, we did polish it,
>> which is what you would ask for, but
what we found is to try to illuminate
that properly, we need a little more
depth to the whole thing. So, we have a
little sample we're going to show you of
what that has to be. What I was
surprised is, you know, how much
engineering goes into this. You know,
you you think art kind of comes together
or you have someone welding in a shop.
That's not the case here.
They're so massive and they're so unique
and the the skin of them and how we're
fabricating that really needed a partner
who can kind of pull all that together.
We've always felt that the family circle
was a really important part of the
story. You know, the Bills Mafia, they
support the team in such a strong way.
>> There are very few things in life that I
think can cause that sort of emotional
reaction and I think sports is one of
them. And so, it's been a great jumping
off point to start with a fan base
that's enthusiastic and just build from
there.
We wanted a place somewhere as they
approached the building where that sense
of family was visible.
>> Let me quote Coach Levy. There's nowhere
else that I'd rather be than right here
and right now. And so when I think of
the family circle, this statement really
emulates that feeling. There's nowhere
else I would rather be. And a moment
like that is a heightened opportunity. I
have liked seeing the personalities come
out of each bison. It was decided to
make it a family of three. You have the
bull, you have the cow, you have the
calf, and each one has a distinct role
in that family. When people come to
visit, they they'll feel that connection
to each one individually and then as a
team, as a united front together.
>> We built a stadium that is both
futuristic and conservative at the same
time with the brick and some of the
materials that we're using on the
outside. You know, with these you're
going to have a vision of the future.
>> The family circle has this raised plint.
This will go around the perimeter. So,
they'll be this blend of color.
>> It's been great. It's been challenging.
There's no doubt about it. There's the
the part where you're trying to get them
done and and make them beautiful. And
then there's the other part is like how
do you celebrate them once they're here?
>> It's a destination for people whether
there's a game here or not. It'll be a
place for people to come together
communally. It'll be a place to
celebrate, you know, what the fan base
and the Bills Mafia have been and what
it means to the entire region.
>> I think the hope is that when fans come
up to them, they're in awe and that they
can see then the statues themselves. It
just doesn't end there. All around um is
part of a greater story of the Buffalo
Bills.